MICHAEL KOLESIDIS

FRONT-END WEB DEVELOPER

Profile

I am a Front-End Web Developer with a diverse background in computer science, economics and the arts. I enjoy being creative and curious, learning and building new, exciting things every day. I am passiotate with frontend development and I aim at creating web experiences that are both functional and beautiful.

Tech Stack

Programming/Scripting Languages















HTML

TypeScript













React Sass Software & Tools



















Linux Illustrator XD Photoshop Figma VSCode Git * Basic knowledge

Sample Projects

JavaScript Software Synthesizer 🜍 🌐

The JavaScript Software Synthesizer is a web application enabling you to make and play music in the browser. It is a software synthesizer utilizing the Web Audio API by implementing a variety of JavaScript libraries.

Technologies: Tone.js, JavaScript, Sass, npm

Landmarks 🗘 🌐

A React web application showing landmarks around the globe. It fetches data from a static dataset, and generates a set of card elements using props, as well as conditional rendering.

Technologies: React, JavaScript, Webpack, npm

3D Cube 🗘 🌐

A 3D cube rotating according to mouse movement. It is created dynamically on load, according to window dimensions.

Technologies: p5.js, JavaScript

Japanese Restaurant 🗘 🌐

A JavaScript single-page application (SPA) showcasing the use of ES6 modules as well as Webpack.

Technologies: JavaScript, Sass, Webpack, npm

Minesweeper Emoji 🗘 🌐

The classic game reimagined and implemented with emojis.

Technologies: p5.js, JavaScript

Sports App ()

A progressive web app allows the user to create tables,

Technologies: JavaScript, CSS

Contact



michaelkolesidis in michaelkolesidis

michaelkolesidis.github.io

michael.kolesidis@gmail.com

+306976941600 (Greece) +447365113313 (UK)

Education

University of Macedonia

MSc Applied Informatics (Ongoing) Thessaloniki, Greece

University of Macedonia

BSc Economics Thessaloniki, Greece

Universitat de Barcelona

BSc Economics (Exchange Student) Barcelona, Spain

University of Sussex

BA (Hons) Drama: Theatre and Performance Brighton, United Kingdom

Certificates

Social Hackers Academy

Frontend Web Development Certificate

University of Sussex

General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR)

University of Sussex

Diversity in the Workplace

Experience

Freelancer

Front-End Web Developer Feb 2022 - Present

Social Hackers Academy

Student Mentor Mar 2022 - Present

Manning Publications

Live Project Beta Tester / Book Reviewer

Nov 2021 - Present

Languages

Greek (Native)

English (Proficient)

Spanish (Intermediate)

German (Basic)

